<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ОГЭ Английский</string>

    <string name="hello">Здравствуйте!</string>
    <string name="enter_name">Введите Ваше имя:</string>
    <string name="name_surname">Имя и фамилия</string>
    <string name="enter_grade">Введите желаемую оценку:</string>
    <string name="grade">Оценка</string>
    <string name="start_preparation">Начать готовиться</string>
    <string name="start_comment">Введите данные, чтобы продолжить</string>

    <string name="oge_main_screen">ОГЭ</string>
    <string name="english">English</string>
    <string name="trainings">Тренировки</string>
    <string name="variants">Варианты</string>
    <string name="theory">Теория</string>

    <string name="individual">Индивидуальная</string>
    <string name="audio">Аудирование</string>
    <string name="reading">Чтение</string>
    <string name="use_of_english">Языковой материал</string>
    <string name="writing">Письмо</string>
    <string name="progress">прогресс 42%</string>

    <string name="cards_watched">просмотрено 24/42</string>

    <string name="variant">Вариант 1</string>
    <string name="solved">решено</string>
    <string name="not_solved">не решено</string>
    <string name="check_variant">Проверить вариант</string>

    <string name="exit">Выход</string>
    <string name="submit">Проверка</string>
    <string name="mistakes">Смотреть ошибки</string>

    <!-- Use of English training section starts here -->
    <string name="uoe_topic1">Множественное число существительных</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic2">Порядковые числительные</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic3">Объектные местоимения</string>

    <string name="app_version">Версия приложения: 0.9</string>
    <string name="email_us">Хотите сообщить об ошибке или внести предложение? Напишите нам!</string>
    <string name="icons_designed_by">Icons designed by Smashicons, Freepik, Gregor Cresnar from www.flaticon.com</string>
    <string name="MA_gratitude">Благодарность Марии Туруновой за наполнение контентом</string>

    <!-- Use of English tasks list (will be replaced with DB soon -->

    <!-- Topic #1 -->
    <string name="uoe_topic1_task1">He was in the bathroom cleaning his ________ when he heard some unfamiliar voices from the veranda.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin1">TOOTH</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer1">TEETH</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task2">His ________ were wet and I gave him a pair of socks to change into. A cup of hot tea and some biscuits soon made the boy feel warm.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin2">FOOT</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer2">FEET</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task3">We arrived at the lake very early. It was cold but in spite of that there were several ________ there. Dad pulled our fishing rods out of the rucksack and we joined the others.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin3">MAN</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer3">MEN</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task4">That was probably true - most ________ in Michael’s class were very competent computer users.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin4">CHILD</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer4">CHILDREN</string>
    
    <string name="uoe_topic1_task5">I felt puzzled and didn’t know what to say. The two ________ at the bus stop looked amused at our conversation and didn’t hide their smiles.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin5">WOMAN</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer5">WOMEN</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task6">She actually looked younger than other ________ of her age and that was probably because of her walking.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin6">WOMAN</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer6">WOMEN</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task7">Anna was glad that the academic year was about to finish. Like most ________ she was looking forward to the summer but not because she wanted to relax.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin7">CHILD</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer7">CHILDREN</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task8">One of the __________ called for the manager and complained.” Ted nervously turned back to his computer. “I didn’t like that job anyway.”</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin8">WOMAN</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer8">WOMEN</string>
    
    <string name="uoe_topic1_task9">My first impulse was to say “no” - unlike most ________ I hated shopping. But Kate sounded so unhappy that I felt sorry for her.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin9">WOMAN</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer9">WOMEN</string>

    <string name="uoe_topic1_task10">Mr. and Mrs. Wormwood were our neighbours. They had two ________.</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_origin10">CHILD</string>
    <string name="uoe_topic1_answer10">CHILDREN</string>

    <!-- Topic #2 -->


    <!-- Audio topics -->
    <string name="audio_topic1">Задание 1</string>
    <string name="audio_topic2">Задание 2</string>
    <string name="audio_topic3">Задания 3&#8211;8</string>

    <!-- Reading topics -->
    <string name="reading_topic1">Задание 9</string>
    <string name="reading_topic2">Задания 10&#8211;17</string>

    <!-- Audio tasks (Задание 1) -->
    <string name="audio_topic1_task1">1. In a swimming pool\n2. In a street\n3. In a travel agency\n4. In a hotel\n5. On a bus excursion</string>

    <!-- Audio tasks (Задание 2) -->
    <string name="audio_topic2_task1">1. The speaker talks about an animal care organization.\n2. The speaker believes environmental education is very important.\n3. The speaker is against keeping exotic animals as pets.\n4. The speaker explains how to protect exotic animals.\n5. The speaker says that common animals are disappearing.\n6. The speaker talks about health reasons for keeping pets</string>

    <!-- Audio tasks (Задания 3-8) -->
    <string name="audio_topic3_task1">On his first day Max came to school</string>
    <string name="audio_topic3_task1_option1">too early.</string>
    <string name="audio_topic3_task1_option2">too late.</string>
    <string name="audio_topic3_task1_option3">exactly on time.</string>

    <string name="audio_topics_3_8_task1">On his first day Max came to school/option/too early./option/too late./option/exactly on time.\n
Max\'s school is located/option/in the park./option/near the library./option/in the city centre.\n
In class Max\'s classmates speak/option/only English./option/their native language./option/Max\'s native language.\n
Max\'s school/option/has computers in every classroom./option/has a special computer room./option/is a computer-free zone.\n
Max is disappointed with school/option/cafeteria food./option/library facilities./option/sports facilities.\n
In the evening Max is going to/option/go to a party./option/do his homework/option/walk around the city.</string>

    <!-- Reading tasks Задания 10-17 -->
    <string name="reading_topic2_text1">\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0The small town in Bavaria is very famous in Germany, because there is the home of the Dassler brothers. They started two well-known sports brands: Adidas and Puma. But their story is not about peace, it\'s about war, disagreement and competition.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0In 1924 Adolf and Rudolf started making shoes and soon had a small shoe business. The elder brother, Rudolf (or Rudi), was a veteran of World War I. He was a good businessman and knew how to sell things. The younger brother, Adolf (or Adi) was more thoughtful and creative. The brothers had 25 workers at the factory and they made 100 pairs of sports shoes every day.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0During the 1936 Olympics, Adi Dassler drove to the Olympic village with a suitcase full of sports shoes. He asked an American sprinter Jesse Owens to wear and run in them. Owens won 4 gold medals and at once the Dassler shoes became popular. The Dasslers were selling 200,000 pairs of shoes each year before World War II.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0We don\'t know much about their lives at the time of World War II. However, in the 1940s they refused to work together any more. Rudolf left the company, moved to the other bank of the river and started a competing shop there. At first he wanted to name his company Ruda, but then he thought about a graceful, quick animal – the puma. And so Puma was born.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0Adi stayed with family business and renamed the company Adidas. He developed the 3-stripe logo in 1941 and registered it as Adidas\' brand. Adi wanted to make a symbol that could be easily recognized by other people and three stripes was a good idea. The stripes show a mountain. You have to climb it if you want to reach the peak or achieve anything.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0The serious conflict between the brothers divided the town into two: the Adidas bank and the Puma bank of the river. It was like a silent war. Only the bravest people could wear their Puma shoes and cross the river to the Adidas side of the town. When people met in the street, they first looked down at each other's shoes. It helped them to decide if that person was an enemy or a friend. What's more, Puma people didn't marry Adidas people. There were Adidas and Puma schools, pubs, shops, restaurants and hotels.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0The brothers never became friendly again or even spoke to each other. Rudi died in 1974 and left Puma to his son. The family sold the company in 1989. Adi died in 1978, his son was the head of Adidas till his death in 1987. Today Puma is controlled by a big French company and Adidas is owned by a number of companies.\n
\u00A0\u00A0\u00A0The "war" was declared completely over in 2009. Employees and workers of both companies shook hands and then played a football match in the Bavarian town of Herzogenaurach. The match was the first joint event for the two companies since 1948. The match ended 7–5 but the teams were not divided into Adidas and Puma. Each team was a mix of Adidas and Puma players.</string>

    <string name="reading_topic2_task1">The brands Adidas and Puma were started in the USA.</string>

    <string name="reading_topic2_task1_real">The brands Adidas and Puma were started in the USA.\n
    One of the brothers advertised the first sports shoes with the help of a famous athlete.\n
    Both brothers called their new company by their own names.\n
    A trip to the mountain gave Adi the idea for Adidas logo.\n
    The people of the town were involved in the brothers’ quarrel.\n
    In Bavaria most people preferred Adidas shoes to Puma shoes.\n
    Now Adidas and Puma belong to the Dassler family.\n
    The results of the football match caused a new outbreak of the war between the Adidas and Puma companies.</string>

    <string name="true_sentence">True</string>
    <string name="false_sentence">False</string>
    <string name="not_stated">Not stated</string>

    <!-- Reading Задание 9 -->
    <string name="headings">Заголовки:</string>
    <string name="texts">Тексты:</string>

    <!-- Writing task -->
    <string name="phrases">Фразы-клише</string>
    <string name="writing_task1">Расставьте слова по порядку:</string>
    <string name="structure">Структура письма</string>
    <string name="writing_task2">Поставьте предложения в правильном порядке, чтобы получилось письмо:</string>
    <string name="linkers">Слова-связки</string>
    <string name="writing_task3">Совместите слова-связки с их русскими эквивалентами:</string>
    <string name="writing_task4">Дополните текст, используя слова-связки:</string>
    <string name="full_answers">Полные ответы</string>
    <string name="writing_task5">Выберите лучший ответ на вопрос:</string>
    <string name="hint">Впишите номера предложений в нужном порядке</string>

    <string name="dont_show">Больше не показывать</string>

    <string name="task9_task1_headings">Выберите заголовок\n1. Good for everyone\n2. Easy to care for\n3. Part of culture\n4. Screen fashion\n5. An innovative idea\n6. Working clothes\n7. Jeans’ labels\n8. Clothes to protest</string>

    <string name="task9_task1_text1">Jeans are one of fashion\'s most long enduring trends. Cowboys wear them but so do supermodels, farmers, presidents and housewives. Ask any group of people why they wear jeans and you will get a range of answers. For some they\'re comfortable and easy – for others they\'re trendy and cool. Jeans mean different things to different people, but they are popular everywhere.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text2">Americans do not have a national folk dress with a long tradition. Blue jeans are probably the most recognisable article of American clothing. They have been part of American life for over 125 years. Blue denim jeans became not only an expression of American fashion but also an element of American identity known around the world.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text3">Jeans were first designed as trousers for farmers and miners in the states of the American West. They quickly grew popular with common people, including cowboys, factory employees and railroad builders. The new trousers were made from a very strong material which did not wear out easily. However, at the same time jeans were very practical and comfortable to wear.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text4">Pockets were the weak point of the miners\' clothes – they easily tore away from the jeans. A man called Jacob Davis had the idea of using metal rivets (fasteners) to hold the pockets and the jeans together so that they wouldn\'t tear. Davis wanted to patent his idea, but he didn\'t have enough money, so he offered Levi Strauss a deal if Strauss paid for the patent. Strauss accepted and started making jeans.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text5">By the middle of the twentieth century, these heavy cotton trousers had become a symbol of opposition for young artists and writers. College students started to wear them to show they were against the Vietnam War. The new trousers were banned in American schools from coast to coast and sometimes in theatres and cinemas.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text6">Jeans are good because they don\'t show the dirt. You can easily go a month without washing them and they don\'t look shocking. They don\'t need to be washed as often as other trousers and you don\'t need to iron them. What's more, because of the strong material you can wear your favorite jeans for years. Even the occasional hole or spot doesn\'t spoil them at all.</string>
    <string name="task9_task1_text7">In the 30s and 40s many people began to spend their spare time watching movies where adventurous cowboys rode horses, fought bad guys and wore blue jeans. The actors made jeans popular in movies and everyone wanted to wear them. Young people wished to imitate the casual "cowboyish" look they saw in films, and they began to wear jeans as casual wear.</string>

    <string name="task9_task1_texts1">Jeans are one of fashion\'s most long enduring trends. Cowboys wear them but so do supermodels, farmers, presidents and housewives. Ask any group of people why they wear jeans and you will get a range of answers. For some they\'re comfortable and easy – for others they\'re trendy and cool. Jeans mean different things to different people, but they are popular everywhere.\n
    Americans do not have a national folk dress with a long tradition. Blue jeans are probably the most recognisable article of American clothing. They have been part of American life for over 125 years. Blue denim jeans became not only an expression of American fashion but also an element of American identity known around the world.\n
    Jeans were first designed as trousers for farmers and miners in the states of the American West. They quickly grew popular with common people, including cowboys, factory employees and railroad builders. The new trousers were made from a very strong material which did not wear out easily. However, at the same time jeans were very practical and comfortable to wear.\n
    Pockets were the weak point of the miners\' clothes – they easily tore away from the jeans. A man called Jacob Davis had the idea of using metal rivets (fasteners) to hold the pockets and the jeans together so that they wouldn\'t tear. Davis wanted to patent his idea, but he didn\'t have enough money, so he offered Levi Strauss a deal if Strauss paid for the patent. Strauss accepted and started making jeans.\n
    By the middle of the twentieth century, these heavy cotton trousers had become a symbol of opposition for young artists and writers. College students started to wear them to show they were against the Vietnam War. The new trousers were banned in American schools from coast to coast and sometimes in theatres and cinemas.\n
    Jeans are good because they don\'t show the dirt. You can easily go a month without washing them and they don\'t look shocking. They don\'t need to be washed as often as other trousers and you don\'t need to iron them. What\'s more, because of the strong material you can wear your favorite jeans for years. Even the occasional hole or spot doesn\'t spoil them at all.\n
    In the 30s and 40s many people began to spend their spare time watching movies where adventurous cowboys rode horses, fought bad guys and wore blue jeans. The actors made jeans popular in movies and everyone wanted to wear them. Young people wished to imitate the casual “cowboyish” look they saw in films, and they began to wear jeans as casual wear.</string>



    <!-- Writing theory-->
    <string name="algorythm">Для написания успешного письма необходимо:\n\n1) Соблюдать объём 100-120 (+-10%) слов, то есть допустимо 90-132 слова. Если написано менее 90 слов, Вы получаете 0 баллов за письмо. Если написано более 132 слов, все слова после 132-го зачёркиваются, то есть окончание письма у Вас отсутствует.
        \n\n2) Соблюдать структуру письма. Для этого нужно заучить наизусть фразы-клише (начало и конец письма) и знать их порядок.
        \n\n3) Использовать несколько слов-связок.
        \n\n4) Дать полные ответы на 3 заданных вопроса.
        \n\n5) Использовать разнообразную лексику и грамматику уровня 9 класса и неформальный стиль письма.
        \n\nСамые распространенные фразы-клише и слова-связки можно найти в других теоретических карточках.
    </string>

    <string name="cliche_1">Moscow*, Russia\nMay 24th**, 2019</string>
    <string name="cliche_2">Dear Ben***,\nThank you for your recent letter. I was glad to hear from you again.\nIn your letter you asked me about …\n\nHope to hear from you soon.\nBest wishes,\nSasha****\n\n* Ваш город\n** Дата Вашего экзамена\n*** Имя, которое указано в задании\n**** Ваше имя
</string>
    <string name="cliche_3">Moscow, Russia\nMay 24th, 2019</string>
    <string name="cliche_4">&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Dear Ben,\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Thank you for your recent letter. I was glad to hear from you again.\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;In your letter you asked me about my future job. Well, I’d like to become a programmer as I believe it’s one of the most important professions today. Besides learning how to code, I will need to use English a lot because with the help of English I can get access to information for programmers written in English. Also, I will be able to cooperate with people from all over the world. However, my parents don’t agree with my choice. They advise me to be an accountant as they believe it brings much more money.\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Hope to hear from you soon.\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Best wishes,\n&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Sasha</string>
    <string name="cliche_5">Обратите внимание, что после адреса, даты и Вашего имени точка НЕ СТАВИТСЯ. После приветствия (Ben) и пожелания перед Вашим именем ставится запятая.\nКаждая часть письма начинается с красной строки или после пропуска строки (на Ваше усмотрение).</string>

    <!-- Uoe theory -->
    <string name="plurals_html">
        <b>Большинство существительных</b>
        \n\nЧтобы образовать множественное число, нужно прибавить к существительному букву <b>-s</b>.
        \nНапример: a dog – dog<b>s</b>; a game – game<b>s</b>; a toy – toy<b>s</b>.
        \n\n<b>Существительные, оканчивающиеся на определённые буквы</b>
        \n\nЕсли существительное оканчивается на <b>-o, -ch, -sh, -s, -ss, -x</b>,  добавляем <b>-es</b>.
        \nНапример: a potato-potato<b>es</b>; a match – match<b>es</b>; a bush – bush<b>es</b>; a bus – bus<b>es</b>; a glass – glass<b>es</b>; a box – box<b>es</b>.
        \n\nЕсли существительное оканчивается на <b>согласная + y</b>, то <b>y</b> меняется на <b>-i</b> и добавляется <b>-es</b>.
        \nНапример: a country – countr<b>ies</b>; a party – part<b>ies</b>; a story – stor<b>ies</b>.
        \n\nЕсли существительное оканчивается на <b>-f</b> или <b>-fe</b>, то <b>-f/-fe</b> меняется на <b>-v</b> и добавляется <b>-es</b>.
        \nНапример: a life – li<b>ves</b>; a leaf – lea<b>ves</b>, a wolf – wol<b>ves</b>.
        \n\n<b>Исключения</b>
        \n\nК исключениям, которые могут встретиться в ОГЭ, относятся следующие:
        \na m<b>a</b>n – m<b>e</b>n
        \na wom<b>a</b>n – wom<b>e</b>n
        \na child – child<b>ren</b>
        \na fish – fish
        \na m<b>ous</b>e – m<b>ic</b>e
        \na f<b>oo</b>t – f<b>ee</b>t
        \na t<b>oo</b>th – t<b>ee</b>th
        \na g<b>oo</b>se – g<b>ee</b>se
    </string>
    
    <string name="numerals_html">
        <b>Большинство числительных</b>
        \n\nЧтобы образовать порядковое числительное, нужно прибавить к количественному числительному буквы <b>-th</b>.
        \nНапример: four – four<b>th</b>, seven – seven<b>th</b>, twenty-six - twenty-six<b>th</b>.
        \n\n<b>Числительные, оканчивающиеся на определённые буквы</b>
        \n\nЕсли числительное оканчивается на <b>-ve</b> (в английском это 5 (fi<b>ve</b>) и 12 (twel<b>ve</b>)),  меняем <u>ve</u> на <u>f</u> и добавляем <b>-th</b>.
        \nНапример: fi<u>ve</u> – fi<u>f</u><b>th</b>, twel<u>ve</u>-twel<b>f</b><b>th</b>.
        \n\nЕсли числительное оканчивается на <b>-y</b> (в английском это 20, 30, 40 и т.д.), то <u>y</u> меняется на <u>i</u> и добавляется <b>-eth</b>.
        \nНапример: twent<u>y</u> – twent<u>i</u><b>eth</b>, sixt<u>y</u> – sixt<u>i</u><b>eth</b>, ninet<u>y</u> - ninet<u>i</u><b>eth</b>.
        \n\nВ числительном 8 добавляется только буква <b>h</b>:
        \neight – eight<b>h</b>
        \n\nВ числительном 9 исчезает буква <b>e</b>:
        \nnin<strike>e</strike> - nin<b>th</b>
        \n\n<b>Исключения</b>
        \nК исключениям относятся числительные 1, 2 и 3:
        \none – first
        \ntwo – second
        \nthree – third
        \n\nОбратите внимание, что в составном числительном (из нескольких слов) меняется только последнее слово, как и в русском языке.
        \nНапример:
        \nthirty-<b>one</b> – thirty-<b>first</b> (тридцать <b>первый</b> — тридцать <b>первого</b>)
        \none hundred and eighty-<b>four</b> - one hundred and eighty-<b>fourth</b> (сто восемьдесят <b>четыре</b> - сто восемьдесят <b>четвёртый</b>)
    </string>

    <string name="yours_bold">Your<b>s</b></string>
    <string name="hers_bold">Her<b>s</b></string>
    <string name="ours_bold">Our<b>s</b></string>
    <string name="theirs_bold">Their<b>s</b></string>

    <string name="possessive_html">
        Притяжательные местоимения отвечают на вопрос <b>Чей? Чья? Чьё? Чьи?</b>
        \nНапример: <b>my</b> room (<b>моя</b> комната), <b>his</b> phone (<b>его</b> телефон).
        \n\nВ английском языке у притяжательных местоимений нет рода, числа и падежа, то есть они не изменяются: <b>моя</b> комната — <b>my</b> room, <b>мои</b> комнаты — <b>my</b> rooms, <b>моей</b> комнаты — <b>my room</b>, <b>мой</b> телефон — <b>my</b> phone.
        \n\nПритяжательные местоимения делятся на 2 группы в зависимости от места в предложении:
        \n1) Притяжательные местоимения, после которых стоит <i>существительное</i> (<b>my</b> <i>keys</i>, <b>his</b> <i>book</i>, <b>their</b> <i>money</i>).
        \n2) Притяжательные местоимения, после которых нет существительного (The keys are <b>mine</b>, Whose book is this? - <b>His</b>, The money is <b>theirs</b>).
    </string>

    <string name="objective_html">
        В английском языке у личных местоимений 2 падежа: именительный и объектный (косвенный: от родительного до предложного).
        \nМестоимения в именительном падеже отвечают на вопросы Кто? Что? и в предложении являются <u>подлежащим</u>.
        \nНапример: <u><b>She</b></u> likes fruit. <u><b>We</b></u> walk our dog twice a day. Can <u><b>you</b></u> open the door?
        \n\nМестоимения в косвенном падеже отвечают на вопросы Кого? Чего? Кому? Чему? Кем? Чем? О ком? О чём? и в предложении являются дополнением.
        \nНапример: Help me! Don’t ask him. They are waiting for us.
    </string>

    <string name="self_html">
        Возвратные местоимения используются, когда <u>подлежащее</u> и <b>дополнение</b> — один и тот же человек/предмет.
        \nНапример: <u>I</u> solved the problem <b>myself</b> — <u>Я</u> решил задачу <b>сам</b>.
        \n<u>He</u> blames <b>himself</b> — <u>Он</u> винит <b>себя</b>. (Сравните: <u>He</u> blames <b>her</b> — <u>Он</u> винит <b>её</b>)
        \n<u>We</u> can’t do it <b>ourselves</b> — <u>Мы</u> не можем сделать это <b>сами</b>.
    </string>

    <string name="passive_html_part_1">
        Пассивный залог используется, когда <u>подлежащее</u> пассивно, то есть не выполняет действия, выраженного <b>сказуемым</b>.
        \nНапример: <u>Книга</u> <b>была написана</b> в 17-ом веке (книга не писала, её кто-то написал). - The <u>book</u> <b>was written</b> in the 17th century.
        \n\nПассивный залог используется, когда:
        \n1) объект важнее того, кто совершает действие: These phones <b>are made</b> in China/Эти телефоны <b>сделаны</b> в Китае. (Телефоны для нас важнее, чем тот, кто их сделал)
        \n2) тот, кто совершает действие, неизвестен: My bike <b>was stolen</b> yesterday/Мой велосипед <b>был украден</b> вчера. (Мы не знаем, кто украл велосипед)
        \n3) тот, кто совершает действие, и так понятен: Our tests <b>will be checked</b> tomorrow/Наши тесты <b>будут проверены</b> завтра. (Понятно, что наш учитель будет проверять тесты)
        \n\nОбщая формула пассивного залога: <b>be + V3</b>. Чтобы употребить пассивный залог в нужном простом времени (Present Simple, Past Simple, Future Simple), возьмём подходящую форму глагола <b>be</b> (быть) из таблицы и добавим смысловой глагол в 3-ей форме
    </string>

    <string name="passive_html_part_2">
        Вчера мой <u>велосипед</u> <b>угнали</b>. - Yesterday my <u>bike</u> <b>was stolen</b>.
        \nКаждый год <u>Москву</u> <b>посещают</b> более миллиона туристов. - Every year <u>Moscow</u> <b>is visited</b> by more than one million tourists.
        \nВ следующем году в нашем городе <b>построят</b> новый <u>стадион</u>. - Next year a new <u>stadium</u> <b>will be built</b> in our city.
        \n\nПассивный залог во временах групп Perfect и Continuous строится по-другому (глагол <b>be</b> ставится в формулу соответствующего времени), но это не встретится в данном экзамене.
    </string>
    
    <string name="wish_html">
        I wish … - разновидность условного предложения. Возможны 2 варианта построения предложений:
        \n<u>I wish</u> he <b>lived</b> here (<u>I wish</u> + <b>V2</b>) – жалеем о том, что он не живёт здесь сейчас.
        \n<u>I wish</u> he <b>had lived</b> here (<u>I wish</u> + <b>had V3</b>) – жалеем о том,что он не жил здесь в прошлом.
        \nВ ОГЭ вам понадобится только формула <u>I wish</u> + <b>V2</b>, поэтому смело ставьте глагол после I wish во вторую форму.
        \nНапример: <u>I wish</u> I <b>could</b> speak French. <u>I wish</u> he <b>came</b> to visit us. <u>I wish</u> we <b>had</b> more money.
    </string>

    <string name="if_real_html">
        Условное предложение - сложноподчинённое предложение, обе части которого относятся к <b>будущему</b> времени. Ситуация реальная, условие может исполниться.
        \nНапример: Если <b>будет</b> хорошая погода, мы <b>пойдем</b> гулять.
        \n\nВ английском языке обе части также относятся к <b>будущему</b> времени, но глагол в части с «если» используется в <u>настоящем</u> времени (Present Simple). То есть: Если <u>есть</u> хорошая погода, мы <b>пойдем</b> гулять. — If the weather <u>is</u> good, we <b>will go</b> for a walk.
        \n\nФормула: <b>If</b> + <b>V/Vs, will V</b>
    </string>

    <string name="if_unreal_html">
        Условное предложение - сложноподчинённое предложение, обе части которого относятся к настоящему времени. Ситуация нереальная, условие не может исполниться сейчас.
        \nНапример: Если бы у меня <b>была</b> сестра, мы <b>бы делили</b> комнату (сестры у меня нет).
        \n\nВ английском языке обе части также относятся к настоящему времени, но глагол в части с «если» используется в <u>прошедшем</u> времени (Past Simple), а в другой части используется <b>would</b> + <b>V</b>. То есть: If I <u>had</u> a sister, we <b>would share</b> a room.
        \n\nФормула: <b>If</b> + <b>V2/Ved, would V</b>
    </string>

    <string name="to_be_html">
        Глагол <b>be</b> имеет особые формы спряжения. Чтобы выбрать нужную форму, обратите внимание на то, в каком времени предложение.
        \nНапример: I <u>passed</u> the exam that’s why I <b>was</b> happy (предложение в прошедшем времени).
        \nThousands of tourists <u>visit</u> Italy every year as it <b>is</b> very famous (предложение в настоящем времени).
        \nI <u>hope one day</u> people <b>will be</b> kinder (предложение о надеждах на будущее).
    </string>

    <string name="modals_html">
        Модальные глаголы выражают отношение говорящего к действию (совет, разрешение, обязанность и т.д.). К ним относятся <b>can, must, should, may, have to</b> и др.
        \n\nМодальные глаголы не изменяются, то есть, не добавляются -s, -ed, -ing.
        \nПосле модальных глаголов следует <u>инфинитив</u>.
        \nВ вопросах модальный глагол ставится в начале предложения, в отрицании добавляется <b>not / -n’t</b> после глагола; вспомогательные глаголы не нужны.
        \n\nНапример:
        \nWe <b>can</b> <u>swim</u>. We <b>can not</b> <u>swim</u>. <b>Can</b> we <u>swim</u>? - настоящее время
        \nWe <b>could</b> <u>swim</u>. We <b>could not</b> <u>swim</u>. <b>Could</b> we <u>swim</u>? - прошедшее время
        \nHe <b>should</b> <u>sleep</u> more. He <b>shouldn’t</b> <u>sleep</u> more. <b>Should</b> he <u>sleep</u> more?
        \nThey <b>must</b> <u>go</u>. They <b>mustn’t</b> <u>go</u>. <b>Must</b> they <u>go</u>?
    </string>

    <string name="degrees_comparison_html">
        В русском языке прилагательные изменяются по родам, числу и падежам (красивый, красивая, красивые, красивыми и т.д.). В английском языке прилагательные не изменяются. Однако можно образовать различные степени сравнения, как и в русском.
        \n\nСтепени сравнения образуются двумя способами: к коротким словам добавляем суффиксы <b>-er</b> (=более) и <b>-est</b> (=самый), к длинным - слова <b>more</b> (=более) и <b>most</b> (=самый).
        \nНапример: tall – tall<b>er</b> – the tall<b>est</b>, interesting – <b>more</b> interesting – the <b>most</b> interesting.
        \n\nКороткие слова состоят из 1 слога (kind, slow, tall) или 2-х слогов, если оканчиваются на -y (happy, funny, crazy). Все остальные слова длинные (peaceful, interesting, dangerous).
        \n\nПри образовании степеней сравнения коротких слов нужно помнить 3 правила написания:
        \n1) Если слово оканчивается на согласная + гласная + согласная, то <b>последняя согласная</b> удваивается: thi<b>n</b> – thi<b>nn</b>er – the thi<b>nn</b>est.
        \n2) Если слово оканчивается на <b>-y</b>, то <b>-y</b> заменяется на <b>-i</b>: happ<b>y</b> – happ<b>i</b>er – the happ<b>i</b>est.
        \n3) Если слово оканчивается на <b>-e</b>, то <b>-e</b> исчезает: nic<b>e</b> – nic<i>er</i> – the nic<i>est</i>.
        \n\nЕсть 2 исключения, которые очень часто встречаются в экзамене. Их нужно запомнить.
        \n<b>Good</b> – <b>better</b> – <b>the best</b>
        \n<b>Bad</b> – <b>worse</b> – <b>the worst</b>
        \n\nПри выполнении заданий обращайте внимание на следующие слова:
        \n<i>than</i> (чем) после пропуска указывает на сравнительную степень (taller <i>than</i>, more interesting <i>than</i>);
        \n<i>the</i> перед пропуском указывает на превосходную степень (<i>the</i> tallest, <i>the</i> most interesting).
    </string>

    <string name="would_html_part_1">
        Косвенная речь — передача одним человеком речи другого.
        \nНапример: Мой друг сказал, что позвонит завтра.
        \n\nВ русском языке глаголы <i>сказал, сообщила, объяснили</i> и т.д. не влияют на время  <b>глагола</b> в самом высказывании.
        \nНапример: Катя <i>сказала</i>: «Мама <b>придёт</b> поздно» - Катя <i>сказала</i>, что мама <b>придёт</b> поздно.
        \n\nВ английском же глаголы в прошедшем времени <i>сказал, сообщила, объяснили</i> и т.д. как бы отодвигают высказывание назад, поэтому время глагола в высказывании тоже меняется на «более прошедшее». Чаще всего первая форма глагола меняется на вторую.
        \n\nВ таблице представлены наиболее употребимые формы глагола в косвенной речи. Постарайтесь понять логику изменений форм глаголов, а не заучивать их.
    </string>

    <string name="would_html_part_2">
        *В ОГЭ проверяется знание правил косвенной речи именно в Future Simple, т.е. при раскрытии скобок нужно писать <b>would V</b> (go → would go, be → would be, come → would come)
    </string>

    <string name="blank"> </string>

    <string name="clarification">Ниже приводятся основные обозначения, используемые в таблице:\nV = verb (глагол)\n+ = утвердительное предложение\n- = отрицательное предложение\n? = вопросительное предложение</string>

    <!-- Content for theory tables -->
    <string name="to_be_heading"><b>Be</b> / быть</string>
    <string name="to_be_1"><u>I/he/she/it</u>    <b>was</b></string>
    <string name="to_be_2"><u>you/we/they</u>    <b>were</b></string>
    <string name="to_be_3"><u>I</u>    <b>am</b></string>
    <string name="to_be_4"><u>he/she/it</u>    <b>is</b></string>
    <string name="to_be_5"><u>you/we/they</u>    <b>are</b></string>
    <string name="to_be_6"><u>I/you/he/she/it/we/they</u>    <b>will be</b></string>

    <string name="present_simple_1"><u>I\nyou\nwe\nthey</u></string>
    <string name="present_simple_2"><u>He\nshe\nit</u></string>
    <string name="present_simple_3">
        Регулярные действия/привычки:
        \nI <b>clean</b> my teeth <u>twice a day</u>
        \nShe <b>swims</b> in the sea <u>every summer</u>
        \n\nРасписание:
        \nThe train <b>leaves</b> <u>at 7</u>
        \nThe TV show <b>starts</b> <u>in 15 minutes</u>
    </string>

    <string name="markers_1">Always, usually, sometimes, often,  never, every day/week/month/year, once/twice/three times a day/week/month/year</string>

    <string name="present_cont_1"><u>I</u></string>
    <string name="present_cont_2"><u>He\nshe\nit</u></string>
    <string name="present_cont_3"><u>We\nyou\nthey</u></string>

    <string name="present_cont_4">
        Прямо сейчас:
        \nI <b>am learning</b> English tenses <u>at the moment</u>
        \n\nПланы на будущее:
        \nWe <b>are visiting</b> our grandparents <u>at the weekend</u>
        \n\nРаздражение:
        \nShe <b>is</b> <u>always</u> <b>crying</b>, I’m fed up with it!
        \n\nВременные ситуации:
        \n<u>This week</u> I <b>am studying</b> for my exams
    </string>

    <string name="markers_2">At the moment, (right) now, always, constantly (раздражение), this week/month/year, today</string>

    <string name="present_perf_1"><u>I\nyou\nwe\nthey</u></string>
    <string name="present_perf_2"><u>He\nshe\nit</u></string>
    <string name="present_perf_3">
        Есть результат (время неизвестно/неважно):
        \nI <b>have lost</b> my keys
        \nShe <b>has broken</b> the vase
        \n\nДействие произошло в период времени, который ещё не закончился:
        \n<b>Have</b> you <b>seen</b> Mark <u>today</u>?
        \nShe <b>has been</b> abroad <u>this month</u>
    </string>
    <string name="markers_3">Already, yet, just, recently, lately, ever, never, today, this week/month/year</string>

    <string name="past_simple_1"><u>I\nyou\nwe\nthey\nhe\nshe\nit</u></string>
    <string name="past_simple_2">
        Действия в прошлом, часто с указанием времени(>=24 часа):
        \nI <b>visited</b> Paris <u>5 years ago</u>.
        \nShe <b>swam</b> in the sea for the first time <u>last summer</u>.
        \n\nПоследовательные действия в прошлом:
        \nAnn <b>cleaned</b> her teeth, <b>had</b> breakfast, <b>got</b> dressed and <b>left</b> for work.
    </string>
    <string name="markers_4">Yesterday, last week/month/year, 2 days/1 week/4 months /10 years ago, in 1995</string>

    <string name="past_cont_1"><u>I\nhe\nshe\nit</u></string>
    <string name="past_cont_2"><u>We\nyou\nthey</u></string>
    <string name="past_cont_3">
        Действие в точное время в прошлом (&lt;24 часов):
        \nI <b>was watching</b> a movie <u>yesterday at 2pm</u>
        \n<u>This time last Friday</u> we <b>were driving</b> to our dacha.
        \n\nДействие в прошлом одновременно с другим действием. Другое действие может быть ДЛИТЕЛЬНЫМ (Past Continuous) или <i>коротким</i> (Past Simple):
        \nMum <b>was reading</b> a newspaper <u>while</u> dad WAS WATCHING the news.
        \nThey <b>were playing</b> Monopoly <u>when</u> grandpa <i>entered</i> the room.
    </string>
    <string name="markers_5">This time yesterday/last Friday, last Sunday evening/at 4pm, when, while</string>

    <string name="past_perf_1">
        Действие ДО <i>другого действия</i> в прошлом:
        \n<u>By the time</u> <i>we came home</i>, dad <b>had</b> already <b>left</b>.
        \nYesterday <i>I started reading</i> the book <b>I had bought</b>.
        \n\nДействие, являющееся причиной <i>другого действия</i>/СОСТОЯНИЯ в прошлом:
        \nMary <i>was crying</i> <u>because</u> she <b>had failed</b> the exam.
        \nSam WAS HAPPY <u>as</u> he <b>had won</b> $100 000.
    </string>

    <string name="markers_6">Before, after, by last Wednesday/ by 3am/by the time, because, as(для указания причины), until</string>

    <string name="future_simple_1">
        Обещания/Надежды:
        \nShe <i>promises</i> she <b>will come</b> to visit us next week.
        \nI <i>hope</i> you <b>will pass</b> the exam.
        \n\nСпонтанные решения:
        \nYour bag looks heavy! I <b>will carry</b> it for you.
        \n\nПредсказания из того, что мы знаем:
        \nJim is <i>the smartest boy in class</i>, he <b>will get</b> everything right on his test.
    </string>

    <string name="markers_7">Tomorrow, next Friday/week/month/year, in(через) a week/a month/5 years</string>

    <string name="reported_present_simple">Present Simple\n<b>(V/Vs)</b></string>
    <string name="reported_future_simple">Future Simple\n<b>(will V)*</b></string>
    <string name="reported_past_simple">Past Simple\n<b>(V2/Ved)</b></string>
    <string name="reported_present_cont">Present Continuous\n<b>(am/is/are Ving)</b></string>
    <string name="reported_past_cont">Past Continuous\n<b>(was/were Ving)</b></string>
    <string name="reported_present_perf">Present Perfect\n<b>(have/has V3)</b></string>
    <string name="future_in_past">Future in the past\n<b>(would V)*</b></string>
    <string name="reported_past_perf">Past Perfect\n<b>(had V3)</b></string>
    <string name="reported_past_perf_cont">Past Perfect Continuous\n<b>(had been Ving)</b></string>

    <string name="reported_example_1">He said, \'I <b>like</b> meat.\' → He said that he <b>liked</b> meat.</string>
    <string name="reported_example_2">She exclaimed, \'I <b>will cope</b> with it!\' → She exclaimed she <b>would cope</b> with that.*</string>
    <string name="reported_example_3">We answered, \'We <b>were</b> there yesterday.\' → We answered we <b>had been</b> there the day before.</string>
    <string name="reported_example_4">They wondered, \'<b>Are</b> you <b>working</b>?\' → They wondered if we <b>were working</b>.</string>
    <string name="reported_example_5">She said, \'I <b>was working</b> at 7pm yesterday.\' → She said she <b>had been working</b> at 7pm the day before.</string>
    <string name="reported_example_6">He said, \'I <b>have lost</b> my credit card.\' → He said he <b>had lost</b> his credit card.</string>

</resources>
